

ravi222bsr@gmail.com

8791700661

Bulandshahr, U.P

.

linkedin.com/in/ravi-kumar-9b78369b in

Deadline Oriented Software Tester with 3.11 years of experience in a manual testing environment. Easily collaborate with developers and project managers to accomplish milestones. Solid history of discovering errors, resolving defects and ensuring client expectations are met with quality.

WORK EXPERIENCE

QA Engineer

SmartBox Ecommerce Solution Pvt Ltd

11/2019 - Present

Noida

Assistant QA Consultant Expedien Esolutions Ltd

02/2018 – 11/2019

Noida

Product Support ExecutiveInfo Edge India Limited

05/2015 – 04/2017

Noida

PROJECTS

SMARTBOX APP (Smartbox Ecommerce Solution Ltd)

- Analyze Requirement Specification to understand the application.
- Review the requirements and prepare test cases.
- Perform Functional Testing, Regression & Retesting, Smoke & Sanity Testing, Database testing.
- Bug Reporting and tracking on JIRA.
- Working on automation Testing with Selenium Webdriver.

GAUHATI UNIVERSITY (Expedien Esolutions Ltd)

- Review the requirement and preparation of Test Cases.
- Performed Functional Testing, Regression & Retesting, Smoke & Sanity Testing.
- Bug reporting and tracking on MANTIS.
- Ensure fixation of Bugs and interacting with developers to resolve defects.
- Proactively learning automation Testing (Selenium).

GOA UNIVERSITY (Expedien Esolutions Ltd)

- Review the requirement and preparation of Test Cases.
- Performed Functional Testing, Regression Retesting, Smoke & Sanity Testing.
- Bug reporting and tracking using MANTIS.
- Ensure fixation of Bugs and interacting with developers to resolve defects.

First Naukri (Info Edge India Ltd)

- Identified and documented the requirements/ enhancements.
- Verifying the enhancements in existing product.
- Interacting with clients/ end users.
- Bug/ Stories reporting and tracking on JIRA.

SKILLS

Manual Testing Functional Testing

Regression & Restesting Test Case Development

Smoke & Sanity Testing Automation Testing

Selenium JAVA TestNG JIRA MS SQL

DBeaver

EDUCATION

MCA (2012-2015)

DR. A.P.J ABDUL KALAM UNIVERSITY, LUCKNOW

BCA (2009-2012)

CCS UNIVERSITY, MEERUT

INTERMEDIATE (2009)

UP BOARD ALLAHABAD

HIGH SCHOOL (2007)

UP BOARD ALLAHABAD

LANGUAGES

English
Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Badminton